Hey Thank You Monica and Laura for for
joining me today
today we are i normal winsome is your
donor conception story and knowing what
you know now what would you change
something along those lines the idea
Cafe will become a platform that anyone
can come to share from their heart and
discuss a meaningful question with other
people that they need to bring
themselves we will assign them people to
talk to based on a topic or question
that is important to them so that's this
what ok see this is my first week
finding individuals and then picking a
time so Monica and I pitched the
question and the time period and then I
reached out to Laura and she is also
joining because we all have that piece
in common that we all have a donor
conception story and we actually all
three of us come to it from a very
different point so I can go first or
whoever wants to go first can go first
I'm good with going whatever um well my
story my background is I was a donor and
this it was like a share program where I
received the IBS services in exchange
for basically half my eggs and you know
they would pay for the procedure so
knowing what I know now actually have a
ton of questions
I'm forgive me I'm trying to stay
straight and it's either ton of
questions for donor concedes or someone
who has actually used donated eggs or
spends so and Laura you are which the
purpose is we're just sharing our story
do you have to add some of the five
minutes you're just sharing your story
no change and then Laura can take a turn
or I will take a turn then the third
person so I didn't explain this very
well I forgot that like everyone
of course and then you have an open
discussion and above what what everyone
sherry brought up for us and have a
conversation the remaining numbers yeah
five minutes so like you said looking at
what I know now being with ancestry and
23andme of course naturally I think most
people start out wondering you know or
their heritage you know the background
as well as I started out just making a
family tree and because I wanted to know
my family history and I want my children
to have all that information and then
you know adding some of the people in
there gives you only two other hits and
I'm like hmm okay I had no idea
looking at my background my mother's
background she said it was always French
but coming from another hint with a
family member we found out that it was
German and looking at 23andme how the
dairy up here the ancestry I import
British Irish so I would assume that I'm
getting that from my grandmother's side
since she was from Ireland so
interesting facts like that in the back
of my mind I'm thinking that as the
children get older my kids myself I had
triplets they will be 16 in October so
I'm assuming that my donated eggs the
donor can see would be around the same
age where they're curious of their
background and I'm sure by now they hear
a lot of people their age talking about
it and wondering about it and getting
surprises and I'm not sure if I'm
explaining this right if you do a DNA
test on ancestry and you've got all
these people popping up from out of
nowhere like
hurtin actually shared a lot of DNA with
me and next thing you know they're
finding a half-sibling which leads them
to other siblings reading some of the
stories I've seen don't conceive
children from the male part they found
20 between 20 and 25 half siblings which
is pretty surprising
so I guess my my background is I'm
really wanting to know you know who
those children or how they were raised
I've had dreams thinking that you know
what if they're raised up in a bad
atmosphere fertility and fertility
sometimes breaks up marriages what if
those children or that child ended up in
a single-parent home or you know the
situation maybe they're in a bad
neighborhood and if this child knows who
find out that they were actually doing
conceived and if they actually find me
how would they kind of feel like would
they feel like in a sense abandoned you
know instead of giving me away even
though I'm just an embryo instead of
giving me away why wouldn't you keep me
around for yourself and I could have
lived a better life
um you know just curious to know is if
they were abused the background things
like that'd I've lately I've had a very
strong yearning that that somebody out
there needs me it may sound crazy but
it's just a feeling that comes to mind
and as something I can't get out of my
head so knowing what I know now I
probably wouldn't have going through the
procedure had I known that you
had I known that the information would
be available and I would not be able to
you know contact a child which I don't
want to interrupt anybody's family leg
but I would like to know how the child
or children grew up what type of parent
they are you know their family
background the people when their family
there are a lot of them it's a mental
issues going around and I just I kind of
feel like I'm on it's more of an ad
watching kind of thing and again I don't
know if I'm really explaining myself
right because it comes out differently
than what it is in my head but I kind of
felt like it was an adoption that I kind
of gave up this child not knowing where
they'll go what type of information I'm
putting them in you know if they'll have
a happy life rough life sad life
how would that channel filled and
they're going to actually meet me you
know how would they feel would they be
accepting of me being their biological
mother or or someone then you know
helped my mommy have me do they feel
like are they feeling out of place I've
read a few stories of delicacy children
and they're stating that they've always
felt in place or that you don't belong
and that they have features that the
parents don't have and it's just I
actually just told my children after
joining the group Sandman finally this
and I did so much children he I know a
lot more about you telling your children
because that sounds very interesting to
me but the five minutes is just over for
a while so hopefully we can talk about
that once we're all back together
chatting Laura would to share would you
like me to share
so I am a donor conceived child i am i
my both of my parents were having very
severe infertility issues but my
mother's issues could be fixed through
she had two rounds of surgery and three
years of hormone therapy and I've asked
her many times I'm like how many sperm
donation sperm donors did you go through
and she's like I don't know well into
the double digits and she was very
determined to have me and when and she
always explains that she was just like I
I thought my doctor just worked magic
she was like she really kind of looked
at her doctor as a like just holy crap
and like look at what he did but she
definitely was but the thing about me
though I was the very very first one
made in my clinic I was the very first
when my doctor ever made and we
definitely know that they cut some
corners they did things not by the book
to make me and that has made me very
aware of I'm very lucky I don't have any
serious medical issues but I I really
got lucky because the story of my my
conception is and I totally joke about
it all the time but in serious it
actually is a very it's really scary
my mom was oscillating on a holiday she
was ovulating on Ramadan and so the
doctor's office was completely closed
and she was like at the point where it's
like dude I can't go through another
month of hormone therapy help me the
hell out and the doctor told her don't
worry about it we'll take care of it
this is what you're gonna do you're
gonna go to this hotel concierge desk
the donors gonna drop his donation off
at the concierge you pick it up and you
and your husband going
I made it yourself exact see your faces
and you're like woo that's its but that
was the thing is there was so many cut
corners at the time because there were I
mean I know there's not a lot of
regulations right now but when I was
made it was it was completely the Wild
West it was absolutely the Wild West um
uh and when my mom explains it she was
and when I talked to her about like did
you know like anything about my donor
and she's like we knew nothing and she
said she said at the time she wouldn't
have even thought to ask about genetics
the only thing I think they were testing
and please I might be wrong on this the
only thing that they were testing at the
time when I was made was sexually
transmitted diseases but I think that
that was it so I have absolutely no idea
what genetic issues was passed on to me
um we known and she said she wouldn't
have even thought to ask about cancer
autoimmune diseases mental illness like
nothing um has anyone had cancer stuff
like that and that is something that is
a little scary for me the fact that not
only do I not know that I'm not even
allowed to have any of that information
my donor father I did find him through
ancestry and I have written to him he
refuses to write to me back um all I
don't want a relationship with him I
don't want money from him I just would
like a comprehensive idea of like look
what what is half of my DNA what is what
am I gonna pass on to my children when
when I have kids and the fact that I
don't have that and it's literally it's
right there it's right over there it's
40 blocks away it is it is possible for
me to have and I'm not allowed to have
it because he needs to remain anonymous
I do find to be I feel like that is
counterintuitive to the actual
infertility industry because the whole
point is yes we
to create life we want to help families
create life but then we don't want to be
able to help the babies live a healthy
life then it's like okay screw it it's
out of our hands now when it's like you
have a responsibility to these children
to make sure that they a survive I mean
there are stories of donor kids died
because they didn't know that they
needed proper screenings there are
stories and and it's small but there are
of donor kids getting matched up with
their siblings on tinder this doesn't
help Society and if the whole point of
infertility doctors and everything is to
help make sure that like people who want
to be able to have their own kids can
have their own kids if this is supposed
to help then we have to go all the way
we have to go all the way we have to
make ensure that the quality of life
sustains and not just to a certain point
and then you're playing roulette at the
kid's life um but I know I know who my
dad is I have found I know that I have
at least three other siblings out there
I know that my biological father also
has a daughter she is my half-sister
which I know she probably has no idea
and that's that actually is a little
hard to know that like I don't I would
love to reach out to her but I know that
I can't I know that that would be wrong
to do I can't do that um that would be
inappropriate of me and I know that but
I don't know her situation I don't know
if she is needing it very much like you
Monica or it's like I want to be there
in case she does and she wants to your
question I always knew something was off
oles knew something was off I was like
was I switched at birth like and I look
exactly like my mother and there are
pictures of her giving birth to me like
I know I'm her kid but something felt
off and I couldn't figure it out and
there was something inside of me that
was like I have simple
I know I do I know I had more and now
I'm finding out that I could have up to
50 for all I know I'm given the years my
biological father was donating and it's
incredible how much your body knows and
I it's the weirdest little phenomenon
and I and I one of my biological sisters
who-who did find me said her she she
said that she felt the same way that
something always felt Oh something
didn't click right and it's just it's so
incredible to me how that happens um and
I know going forward if I have and this
is again and I want to say this no
judgment on anybody you know you live
your life the way you want to live your
life but if I was struggling with
infertility I wouldn't do a donor
conceive child I would um I it's just as
my as what I have gone through um I I
think that it records the five minutes
but this is clearly a subject we need
more than five minutes each to to talk
about I'm learning I'm learning how this
goes so I'm just gonna pause you Laura
and I'll share mine and then I'll
unpause all of us and we can each you
can talk for a bit so I'm just gonna try
to keep in mind that I have five minutes
hmm it's harder to tie myself I am a
single mom by choice I was dating a man
eight years ago and he didn't want to
have kids and I did and I went on like I
don't even know like a dozen first dates
and I was just in a depression and I
didn't want to meet a man I wanted a
baby and so I went through the process
of finding a donor I really wanted to
have a known donor so that my kid could
know who their genetics was and reach
out if they wanted to I didn't want that
to be a mystery for them and so I went
on known donor registry I think it was
called I think it still is called that
but it's nowhere near the same as it was
then and I found an amazing man who has
his own children that he
phrasing he lived locally and that's one
of the reasons I chose him he had one
daughter at the time he since went on to
have three other kids that he's raising
as well as another donor child and but
soon after my daughter was born he moved
out east so he moved like a four-hour
flight away and I that's so that's
basically my dad my donor story I'm a
single mom I'm still a single mom and my
child is about to turn seven at the end
of the year what I would change now is I
would always pick him as the donor
because he gave me the most amazing
daughter ever and I know she was
supposed to be here I know that she was
calling to me from the other side I also
ended up getting pregnant my very first
month trying with this man like it was
like she was waiting like it was just
like she she came she also has her own
feelings about being donor conceived
even though she's not even seven yet she
recently told me that she really like
feels angry that she doesn't have a dad
and so I've reached out to him which is
what I would change I would have
maintained the contact with him much um
much more than I did
she's now like I said almost seven and
I've now scheduled bi-weekly
conversations with him on on what's up
so they can see each other cuz he's an
amazing man and I know that he wants to
know her and she wants to know him and
whatever relationship they develop will
be their own brands like their own thing
isn't he's not raising her he's not her
dad but he is her genetic half and she
gets to know that and she has to have
the emotions and the feelings she has
towards it and my job is to navigate
those because I would never change
having her like this planet needs her
exactly how she is and she wouldn't have
been created any other way like I
wouldn't go back and get married and
have a partner and do it that way
because it wouldn't be her and also
there's something about us and being
like one mom one kid that works really
well for for both of our personal
journeys that is amazing
but I'm glad I used to know
if I would have went back and rethought
it I would have picked one like I picked
him because he was here for a reason I
wanted him to be like an uncle in her
life but then he his life changed and he
moved out east and so you know things
things change and again then I wouldn't
have her and she is so amazing and he's
amazing and I really loved him he's one
of my favorite people I kind of get
offended now and I hear people talk
about their dead dads it's like donor
dad's like he's just a donor I'm like he
gave me the most amazing gifts I've ever
gotten ever and I love him he's one of
my favorite people and I picked him
because I loved his energy and I loved
who he was and so that is my five
minutes I will know and pause and we can
have a I mean unmute you guys were
positive it's needed so thank you both
for sharing but thank you for me yeah
yeah and now we can ask questions of
each other and or you know have a
conversation for the next 10 minutes
okay so do you believe when you did you
was he a known donor that's your friend
okay this purpose I didn't know him
before he wasn't like a friend of mine
but we met on this hello Laura can you
hear us
Laura fries yeah whether if I take her
out and then she can come hopefully come
back in I can see if she's moving in
there mine isn't are you too frozen to
now Monica no we're having connection
issues see if people come back in
hopefully they come back in if you want
some talking to myself that was an
interesting one you learn as we go
right click I'm just gonna go I'm just
copying and pasting this see it works
I thought they might be back in perfect
like do it in another window to get
people to rejoin the area Florida gonna
come back as well okay nice you probably
love connection along with me yeah
though the fact that it both happens
makes me think it might be mine if I'm
the one streaming it to YouTube so I
don't know there we go Laura's back
don't wanna kick I can all go in live
these are the things that happen yeah so
I found also I wanted to say Monica I
dunno although they didn't want to come
on here I'm in community with two moms
who did use donor eggs to conceive and
carry their children and those children
which they're younger than mine are both
very happy well-adjusted loved beyond
measure in their families I think there
is I don't want to say there's a big
difference between sperm and egg
donation but there is a difference
between sperm and egg donation like
having you're saying you still carry
them you still you don't I mean like and
I wanted to know from you Lorna when or
how old were you when you found out what
you were 14 yes yeah and I think that's
a big piece of it these kids also know
from the time they're born it's part of
their story it's part of their
conception story I'm and to let let you
also Monica nor I and I mean again I
know that I'm an individual in this and
I see I see a lot of comments from
people
saying like you know they are upset at
their donors for feeling abandoned I do
not hold that at all whatsoever um my
parents are my parents and I know the
one of the things that I wrote to my
donor father when I first tried contact
him was I thanked him I told him you
made my mother's dreams come true and he
did um
and I am so even even if I never had
contact with him even if like I don't
know who he is what kind of person he is
but I will always always be grateful to
grateful to him for the fact that he did
what he did and as strange as my
conception story is and I always tell my
parents I'm like there's no way for you
guys to expect me to have that
conception story and me not to become a
comic like you shouldn't be surprised
that I'm like not a doctor like sorry
guys like what to expect here I have no
ill will I do I would the only person I
have any kind of ill-will towards is my
doctor because the doctor was really it
was like I'm lucky my mom is lucky you
were really playing fast and loose with
her in my life and I understand he was
young I understand that this was new
I understand there's no regulations and
I understand that he was really just
trying to create life but from what it
sounds like he also was kind of aware
that he was he wasn't acting ethically
and he did know better um and I've tried
to talk to my doctor and to ask him like
who's my donor do I have and I'm even
straight-up asked him is does cancer run
in my family is there anything like this
and he was like no I would have never
used a donor who has that and now I'm
realizing that I'm like no dude you were
you were one you were lying there's just
been some shitty stuff like that with
um and I and I do get frustrated that
there is no protection for donor kids
that really sucks there's way more
protections for donors than donor kids
and I feel like that's not ethical
and then Laura when you when you talking
about a headline that were used on with
cancer I know when I went like you said
the only thing making us lose STDs they
don't not even sure they even had me do
a real background check his horse you
know your parents have this have you
ever had I got a disciplinary anything
you know is I could have had cancer at
the time and put anything there and
their main concern was I mean to me it's
money money money and they move you
through the process so fast
yeah you have an opportunity to really
think I use my own eggs and my husband's
you know his firm that promise I only
have one flow note fallopian tube so my
chances were very slim so they're like
you know I went there from informations
first kernels in the levant procedure
and they said hey look at it it's weed
and I have a couple that's willing to
pay for it provided using your eggs with
them I'm like okay that sounds like a
billing but he just from there it's just
move move move sign it sign that take
this medication do this and that and
there's no let's say there's no
counselor in the area in that sense hey
look you know this the deal you will
never be able to contact the parents or
this child are you sure this is
something that you want to do yeah when
I went it
no quickly you don't have time to say
hey I'm gonna go talk to counsel about
this or just look at some look for
somebody who's vented and we were we
lived in Germany at the time my husband
was military and we came back to New
Jersey to actually do the procedure so
within the timeframe we had we were
there for three months within that
timeframe and me wanting to have a child
you know so bad I feel like they played
on you know a plate preyed on my
weakness and she wants a kid so let's
give you this we can get paid by doing
this and that and get her medication
everything now before she changed mine
so had I known how you know how I feel
now I just suddenly before might start
at these groups doing this as I suddenly
I had this urge and just came to my mind
it was like it's no strong okay there's
a king up get it needs me really wants
to get in touch with me and I don't know
where it came from it was just a really
strong feeling and Jubilee like you said
and I told my my girls I have two girls
in the boy when I my son's autistic so
he wouldn't have understood but I sent
my girl thing on my husband's like no no
no you starting up a whole new thing
you're in a brunette world or something
like that and I'm like okay looking up
on women's groups and websites you know
just telling your kid as early as
they're able to understand so I waited a
lot took a couple of days and actually
sat them down and I said okay you know
mommy helped another couple had children
so and I gave her some of my eggs and to
that you may have one or more hair
sisters and brothers surprisingly they
were like okay
I was totally shot they're like okay I
said well how do you feel about that
like how would you feel if we happen to
meet or something she said I don't
really care it will just like it would
be cool to have another brother sister
but you know if we meet them or not
it was no big deal - then they burst and
also easily I'm like I sweat it all
these years and I totally did not expect
that but again I have this journey and I
don't know where it came from
call it weird or whatever but it's just
so strong right now
I meant to the point where I just like
the DNA test who every site and I
uploaded the free must every say and I'm
like okay this kid's gonna find me
stronger if they don't now they're going
to be able to win the 18 I'm like what
if somebody else puts in their name
because 18 and uses his child D&E and
all these crazy things going through my
mind but like Laura you answered my
questions was like you know
automatically felt like like he didn't
belong and was that before or after you
were told
oh I have two full genetic siblings I
was raised by my parents I'm also felt
like I didn't belong like very natural
thing to have happen it's just that then
you like I was like am i adopted like
what's going on here you going to look
like both my parents in fact my sister's
below me if he doesn't look like us
there's always that like grass is
greener like why isn't my dad like the
masculine dads that you know have a
shotgun on the porch and why isn't my
mom that like I think we all have a
piece of that is it necessarily because
of donor conception but say there is
something
I can't any time I've ever talked to
someone who has adopted my sister is
adopted I do have like my dad from his
first marriage adopted my sister and my
sister always knew she was like I always
knew and it it is and this isn't you to
downplay anybody else's emotions but
there there is something that you know
it is something it's not just a you know
Ella you know it's not I can't explain
it but it is there is something so deep
anywhere you just know like something's
off I know I know this there's nothing
off here and my sister knew she was new
and I what age uh she was told when she
was like 10 10 I believe um that one I
mean that was a bit of a different
situation because that was from my
father's first marriage so he was
dealing with him and his first wife what
I was told though my parents told my
pediatrician like look she's a sperm
donor baby and that was a big
conversation between my pediatrician and
my parents and while my pediatrician
actually told my parents do which needs
to know about the age 11 that's when you
should tell that's what I didn't age
where she's gonna understand it and
it'll be fine and it needs to come from
her dad and my dad was very very scared
to tell me and I understand why um I get
why he was nervous about it I think he
was just worried that I wouldn't look at
him as my dad anymore which is not true
at all but so by the time I got to 14
and my pediatrician found out that I
still didn't know she got kissed
apparently and she was like no you have
to tell her now and I'm very glad that
they did I didn't um I have no
resentment at all and again this is just
me
I have no resentment um I know I and I
do have to say you you
to tell your kids there have been people
when there have been people there like
well I would never tell my kid and I'm
like that's wrong you have to tell your
child you have to you have to add an
early age whether they are I mean
adopted or donor as especially adopted I
mean I feel like and this was always a
and it's something that I even talked
about in my stand-up is like it's it's
easier to explain adoption to a
two-year-old it's much harder to explain
sperm donation to a two-year-old um I
did it honestly I'd love to know how I
eat like an applet um the same way I
wonder if she wasn't donor conceived
like I feel like it's biology it's like
we watched yeah it was on YouTube of
like this is what happens this is what
is the how life is creepy but honestly
tell your kids young is as young and
it's like they they're oh they're gonna
look at you like you're the parents may
be very clinical logical you have to
tell your kids because now with ancestry
and 23andme in it anonymity does not
exist it's gone it's it doesn't exist so
this is our new world and it's also you
owe it to your kids that's a huge part
of their truth and it's a huge part of
their fundamental biology they have a
right to know and they have the right to
know their medical history - which is
another issue that I obviously have I
agree and again usually this is a half
an hour conversation and just like the
five minutes wasn't enough a half an
hour has not been enough but I have to
go cook for my kid so I'm going to need
to wrap this up closing statements um I
would like to do another segment if
you've learned on doing another one so
Laura you answered a lot of my questions
and I do appreciate that and as far as
the medical thing I think that is a big
big issues towards the parent being able
to know even before waiting okay if you
find out after you child is 10 or
whatever
that they have a thyroid problem which I
do it's you don't know it and if thyroid
can be make you a lot worse off than I
thought I had a friend that actually
died in his sleep because you know he
had stage 4 cancer women thyroid luckily
I have it but I have it runs in my
family so that's another thing I think
about the child that's something that
they should know and that we as donors
would we should have some type of access
to at least say hey I want to give this
medical information to the parents who
can see you know from my eggs if it's
not for the you know just what a parents
benefit before the child it could save
their life no no well that's what I'm
saying is like where we really have to
we have to make decisions because if we
really if the whole infertility industry
is like their whole point is we want to
create life it's do you want to create
lives do you want to help out and
fertile infertile parents or do you just
want to make money and that's there and
I know you if you genuinely want to help
these parents out if you want to help
create life and you need to figure out a
way for the kids to be able to have a
good quality life to make sure that
their health is number one if you just
care about money than it is business as
usual but you got to admit it that's the
difference and even if it's in their
slogan you know we care about you you
know care about creating life for you
yeah but it didn't stop it then yes you
care about creating life because you're
getting paid for it yeah but it's for
most of these places that I know of 99%
will that's it they leave it at that you
pay us we get you pregnant and that's it
you don't need to know background why
would we even bother doing honest
testing you know that's money coming out
of our pocket if they don't have an
teenee they're good to go you know that
and I ever get it but it's AIT's again
it's a short-sighted thing and it's not
thinking about the long term and that's
the difference I think that's the change
that has to happen with the infertility
and infertility industry is we need to
think long term not just short term not
just about like boom bang that's
pregnant but long time but my closing
statement would be I and I'm very
touched by both of your how you both how
much Jubilee you're how much care you
took to finding the right donor and
Monica the fact that you care so much
about where your eggs kind of ended and
if those kids are okay it's really
touching as a donor kid to hear the to
hear that that you guys you guys did
that much thought and care um and that
does mean a lot and my my closing
statement as it's going to be for as
long as it needs to be it is I'm on I'm
on ancestry I'm on 23andme I am trying
to find my siblings because I know more
and more are out there fine I'm there
our we know that our father is a hundred
percent Ashkenazi Jewish and we know
that at least uh come find me guys I'm
there right you can follow her story on
her channel it's just channel called
it's my name it's Laura hi h IG h / fect
i will put its link to it in the
description once i put this up on friday
eggs you don't want to scoop your video
coming on Thursday and if you want
Monica if you want us to connect to you
in case maybe your donor children are
watching at some point when they figure
out their donor kids and they're
searching on YouTube and this pops up
you're like ah that looks like maybe she
could be mine I don't know the world now
between the genetic side and the
internet we there is no there is no and
yeah that blur number is a big thing
that you know a lot of people have but
that donor number can make a huge
difference yeah absolutely and known
donor just known sibling right I don't
know the one where you find
your siblings I'm sure Laura know who's
doing registering okay there were pages
right right yes she's also I think all
right well thank you both
I'm going to end the broadcast now all
right thanks bye